FARHAN CHAUDHRY

Junior Software Developer

London N16 | 07805 443 4654 | mohammed.f.chaudhry@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

PERSONAL STATEMENT

From a young age, I have always enjoyed technology, problem solving and figuring out how things work. Mechanical Engineering suited my strengths well, and the opportunity to study in Singapore ignited a passion for travel within me. Since leaving university I have worked in the tech industry and in a sabbatical break from my most recent job I decided to commit to a career change. My enjoyment of problem solving as well as the enormous potential of what can be built and designed through code led to me wanting to become a Software Developer and enrolling at Northcoders.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages JavaScript, SQL, Python, Matlab, C
- Back End Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, Docker, AWS
- Front End React, HTML5, HTML, CSS
- Testing Jest
- Data & Analytics Google Data Studio
- Documentation Suites Microsoft Office and Google Workspace
- Project Management Jira
- CAD SolidWorks

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer - Northcoders

Jul 2023 - Oct 2023

- 13-week full-stack web development bootcamp focusing on JavaScript.
- During the course I developed a variety of technical experience:
 - Fundamentals Core JS, coding best practises, pair programming, Git version control, TDD, OOP
 - Back-end Asynchronous programming, APIs (Express), databases (SQL).
 - Front-end React, DOM, semantic HTML, CSS
- Solo project: NC News Successfully built a news aggregation app, users can log in view and submit articles, filter by topic, comment and vote on articles. I applied many of the front and back end technologies I learned into this project. Tech Stack: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, HTML, CSS
- Group project: SafeTrakr mobile app helping people to travel safely, enabling users to automatically text
 designated contacts when they leave, arrive or are in transit. Tech Stack: Node.js, Expo, React Native, Firebase

Senior Installer & Operations Manager - Klevio, London

Jan 2019 - Jun 2023

- Managed installation of Klevio devices globally, leading the systems integration process and managing a team
 of installers
- Led installation process design improvements and ran a project to enable international scalability
- Project-managed our largest implementations (e.g. NHS Property Services), navigating geographical, capacity and time constraints
- Oversaw logistics and procurement; built an in house inventory system, maintained relationships with our suppliers
- Developed tools to gather information concisely from our customers and used data to produce reports & dashboards to inform our operational decision making
- Ran a weekly operations meeting to problem-solve issues across operational, commercial and product development teams
- Processed applications and led interviews of potential operations team members

IT Consultant - Praesto Consulting, London

Jan 2018 - Nov 2018

- Primarily worked on an Oracle Customer Hub (OCH) Replatforming project at a large UK based client
- CRM project where I took the lead on Data Quality using Oracle EDQ. Oracle Database compatibility and full
 integration with Siebel

 Developed thorough solutions to data cleansing, matching, clustering and enrichment problems, closely following project functional requirements

Private Tutor - Lanterna Education, London

Sept 2016 - Dec 2017

- Tutoring IB Mathematics and Physics at both Higher and Standard level. Sessions conducted one-on-one
 online, and to classes of 4-12 students at Regent's University, London, Folkuniversitetet, Stockholm & Bavarian
 International School, Munich
- Developed and implemented comprehensive lesson plans which accommodate specific levels of learners whilst also offering support to make sure each student can grasp the course material

American University of Beirut - Summer Intern

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

IAESTE work placement overseeing infrastructure and maintenance systems at Lebanese university. I was
exposed to an unfamiliar working environment which I found both challenging and rewarding

VOLUNTEERING

Sep 2010 - May 2012

Tutored GCSE level maths to students at Ricards Lodge High School, Wimbledon and taught PE to Year 4 boys at Raynes Park High School with behavioural issues such as ADD and autism

- Both groups presented unique teaching challenges in very different fields, requiring proactive, dynamic and sensitive solutions to overcome issues in understanding
- Helped me to understand the importance of developing motivation in students to encourage enthusiasm in their
 education, as well as skills such as organisation, patience and understanding ones position of responsibility,
 essential to teaching

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering with a Year Abroad (MEng) - Imperial College London Upper Second Class Honours (2:1) | Accumulated average: 69.6%

2012 - 2016

Upper Second Class Honours (2:1) | Accumulated average: 69.6% 4th Year completed at National University of Singapore (NUS)

- 2nd Year Group Project: Design Project; designed manufactured a replacement rear wheel assembly to motorise a push scooter
- 3rd Year Design, Make & Test (DMT) Project: Sustainability; design and manufacture of a low-cost pyrolysis
 reactor for implementation in rural India
- 4th Year Individual Project: Optics; collaborative project with A*STAR Singapore developing a system capable
 of simultaneous spatial and spectral data acquisition

King's College School, Wimbledon

2003 - 2012

- International Baccalaureate (IB): 42/45 with 3 at Level 7 including Physics and Chemistry
- GCSE: 11 at A* including Mathematics, English, Sciences

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Sport Keen rock climber having picked up the sport in 2015 when I was at NUS. I have had outdoor climbing
 experience in the UK, France, Thailand and Serbia. Cricket First XI at school and a member of Imperial Cricket
 society. Team-focused sport in which I've had success as both batter and bowler. Recommenced playing socially
 in summer 2023
- Music Music enthusiast and record collector. Picked up DJing in university and have played out on boat parties and clubs in both London and Singapore
- Languages Working knowledge of Spanish, Urdu and French. Teaching myself Dutch through audiobooks and mobile apps
- Video Editing Self-taught hobby, also encompassing post-production. Created videos with focus on fast paced editing to music. Owner of a YouTube channel with over 1000 subscribers. I was active on YouTube from approximately 2008-2012